Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/shivanisiroya (LinkedIn) www.tala.co (Company)

Top Skills

Due Diligence Valuation

Finance

Languages

Hindi

Gujarati

French

Shivani Siroya

CEO & Founder at Tala (We're Hiring!)

Santa Monica

Summary

Shivani Siroya is the founder and CEO of Tala, the leading financial technology company in emerging markets. Millions of people have borrowed through Tala's smartphone app, which provides instant, personalized credit to underserved customers in East Africa, Southeast Asia, and Latin America. Tala is backed by leading venture and impact investors including PayPal, Revolution, IVP, Ribbit Capital, Data Collective, and Lowercase Capital. Earlier this year, Forbes named Tala as one of the top 50 FinTech companies in the world, and Tala's work has been highlighted by the New York Times, the Financial Times, the Wall Street Journal, TED, and TechCrunch, among others. Tala is headquartered in Santa Monica with additional offices in Nairobi, Manila, Mexico City, and Bangalore.

Prior to founding Tala, Shivani held a variety of positions in global health, microfinance, and investment banking, including with the United Nations Population Fund, Health Net, Citigroup and UBS. Shivani is an Aspen Institute Finance Leader Fellow, a WEF Young Global Leader, Senior TED Fellow and Ashoka Fellow. She is also on the board of Stellar. She holds a M.P.H from Columbia University and a B.A. from Wesleyan University.

Experience

Tala (formerly InVenture)
CEO and Founder
January 2013 - Present (7 years 8 months)
Global

Tala is a mobile technology and data science company that is unlocking financial access, choice and control to underserved people globally. Tala has developed a smartphone app that instantly evaluates and understands customers using only the data on their devices and delivers personalized and customized financial services in minutes.

World Economic Forum Young Global Leader January 2016 - Present (4 years 8 months)

Geneva Area, Switzerland

The Forum of Young Global Leaders is a unique and diverse community of the world's most outstanding, next generation leaders. Bold, brave, action-oriented and entrepreneurial, these individuals commit a portion of their time to jointly shape a better future and thereby improve the state of the world. Set up as an independent, not-for-profit foundation under the Swiss government, the Forum of Young Global Leaders is an integral part of the World Economic Forum.

Health Net

Financial Consultant - Corporate Strategy and M&A August 2009 - December 2012 (3 years 5 months)

Citigroup

Analyst

September 2008 - December 2009 (1 year 4 months)

United Nations Population Fund

Analyst

May 2006 - September 2008 (2 years 5 months)

Janani / Vanthasali through Columbia University Earth Institute Consultant/Analyst January 2007 - September 2007 (9 months)

PricewaterhouseCoopers

Associate

January 2005 - December 2005 (1 year)

UBS Financial Services

Analyst - Equity Research

June 2004 - December 2005 (1 year 7 months)

Credit Suisse

Analyst

June 2003 - August 2003 (3 months)

Credit Suisse First Boston

Analyst June 2002 - August 2002 (3 months)

Education

Wesleyan University
BA, Government and International Relations

Columbia University in the City of New York
MPH, Econometrics and Quantitative Economics and Health Economics